Yeah!
짜잔!
On the 15th of May, in the jungle of Nool,
5월 15일 눌루랄라 정글 속
in the heat of the day, in the cool of the pool,
더위를 피해 웅덩이에서
he was splashing, enjoying the jungle's great joys,
신나게 물장난을 하며 놀던 중
when Horton the Elephant heard a small noise.
코끼리 호튼은 작은 소릴 들었습니다
-Horton!
- 호튼!
Good morning, class. Are you ready?
안녕, 학생들! 준비됐지?
-Yeah! -Jump on board!
- 네! - 탑승 실시!
Look out below!
모두 비켜!
Tommy's on board. Katie, you there?
토미는 탑승 완료! 케이티, 준비됐지?
Okay.
좋아
There it is.
저것 봐
This is one of the jungle's most amazing creatures, the leaf bug.
정글 최고의 엽기 곤충 잎벌레야
In order to protect itself from predators, it disguises itself as a leaf.
안 잡아먹히려고 나못잎처럼 위장해
This one's got quite a grip. Come on, little buddy.
엄청 곽 붙어있네 좀 떨어져!
Don't be shy.
해치지 않아!
I guess I was mistaken, kids.
내가 잘못 봤나?
There are obviously no leaf bugs in this area. Even if...
이쪽엔 잎벌레가 없나 봐
No, they're on me!
엄마야!
I think I swallowed one!
삼켰나 봐
Tommy! Pull it out!
토미, 빼내줘!
Uh, okay.
알았어요
Then humpfing a "humpf" was a sour Kangaroo,
그때 까칠한 잘난척 여왕
the type who's convinced she knows better than you.
캠거루 여사가 나타났죠
She made every law and enforced every rule
그녀의 말은 곧 법이랍니다
as self-proclaimed head of the jungle of Neal.
그녀는 자칭 "정글의 여왕 이죠
Why can't I play with the other kids, Mom?
친구랑 놀고 싶어요
How many times have I told you that
품위 없는 쌍것들이나
the jungle is no place to act like a wild animal.
들짐승처럼 뛰노는 거야
My, that Horton certainly is eccentric.
호튼은 참 괴짜야
And the children are learning so much from him.
그래도 애들이 많은 걸 배우잖아
Learning to be a bunch of harebrained half-wits!
재한테 배워봤자 바보 돼!
And that's why my Rudy is pouch-schooled.
그래서 루디는 홈스쿨로 배워
So while Kangaree stood there, - sneering a sneer...
캠거루가 비웃고 있을 동안.…
Horton, that was the best time I've ever had in my life!
오늘 최고로 재밌었어요!
..once again, the speck floated right by Horton's ear.
…티골은 또 호튼의 가를 맵돌았고
Then he heard it again, just a very faint yelp,
그 작은 소린 또 들려왔죠
as if some tiny person were calling for help.
작은 사람의 비명처럼
And you know what he thought?
호튼은 생각했죠
Why, he thought that there must be someone
그 티끌 속에
on top of that small speck of dust!
분명 누가 있는 거라고
Or even a family, it just might be so,
어 한 가족일 수도 있고
a family with children just starting to grow.
애들도 있을지 모른다고
I want to live!
살려줘요!
I gotta go. Katie, you're in charge!
난 가야 돼 케이티, 네가 맡아줘!
Wait!
잠깐만!
-Come back! -Watch it!
- 돌아와! - 조심해!
One more! One more! One more!
하나 더! 하나 더! 하나 더!
-l hear someone coming! -Give me those!
- 뭔가 온다! - 줘봐
-Wait! -Sound the alarm!
- 기다려! - 경보를 울려!
Excuse me. Pardon my stampede!
판 쳐서 미안해!
Sorry, Wickershams! I promise I'm gonna clean all this up later!
미안해, 위커샘 형제! 나중에 꼭 치울게!
Bring the ammo!
폭탄 가져와!
I love the smell of bananas in the morning.
바나나탄 향이 오늘따라 달콤하군
Banana in the hole!
바나나 장전!
Come on, guys! We're all mammals!
이럴 거야? 같은 포유류끼리!
I feel the diplomatic process is beginning to break down.
외교로 해결하던 시대가 그립군
There you are! I got you!
여기 있구나! 잡았다!
Hi, kids!
안녕!
Wow.
와!
There.
됐어
Now you're safe.
이젠 안전해
I know I heard you say something. I just know it.
네가 말하는 걸 분명 난 들었어
Where are you?
어디 있는 거야?
Horton!
호튼!
Sorry!
미안!
I just... There was this speck, and it called out for help.
이 티끌이 도와달라고 비명을 질러서
-And I was... -The speck called out for help?
- 그래서.… - 티끌이 도와달랬다고?
Well, not the speck. I mean, that's ridiculous.
티끌이 아니고 그건 말도 안 되지
Is that what you thought I meant? No, the speck can't call out for help.
티끌이 어떻게 도와달란 말을 해?
Come on, get real.
말이 돼? 농담도!
No, there's a tiny person on that speck that needs my help.
티끌 속의 작은 사람이 도와달랬어
Absurd. There aren't people that small!
말도 안 돼 그렇게 작은 사람은 없어!
Well, maybe they aren't small.
그들이 작은 게 아니라
-Maybe we're big. -Horton.
- 우리가 큰 건지도 몰라 - 호튼
No, really, think about it. What if there was someone way out there
한 번 생각 좀 해봐 어 우리도 누가
looking down on our world right now?
내려다보고 있을지 몰라
And to them, we're the specks.
그의 눈엔 우리가 작은 티끌 같겠지
And then, maybe someone else will come along and say,
그는 친구에게 얘길 할 거고
“Oh, there can't be people that small", and the first guy would say,
친구는 “삐지 마' 라고 하겠지
“Are you calling me a liar?”
그가 '날 못 믿어?' 하면
And the second guy would say, “If the shoe fits, wear it!"
친구는 '말이 되는 소릴 해야지' 할 테고
And now the fists are flying, and the first guy picks up a brick,
그럼 그는 열받아 짱돌 들고 외칠 거야
and you might want to zip up the pouch for this next part.
애 못 듣게 귀 막아
“All right, fat boy, you want some of this..."
'야, 뚱보, 데질래?'
-Horton! -What?
- 호튼! - 왜?
There is nothing on that speck.
티끌엔 아무것도 없어
-But I heard. -Did you?
- 소릴 들었어 - 그래?
Really? Oh, my.
정말? 맘소사
Then how come I don't hear anything?
그런데 왜 난 안 들리지?
Well...
그야.…
If you can't see, hear or feel something,
안 보이고 안 들리고 안 만져지면
it doesn't exist.
그건 없는 거야
And believing in tiny, imaginary people
작은 사람이 있다고 믿는 건
is just not something we do or tolerate,
이 눌루랄라 정글에선
here in the jungle of Nool.
절대 용납받지 못할 일이야
Really? Because I bet if I really tried, I could find somebody who'd believe
그럴까? 찾아보면 분명 날 믿어주는 사람이
-what I've been saying. -You will do nothing of the sort.
- 있을 텐데 -안돼
You will not breathe a word of this lie to anyone else, especially the children.
그런 거짓말 떠들고 다니지 마 애들에겐 특히!
I do not want you poisoning their minds with this nonsense.
그런 소리 들으면 애들 버려
Our community has standards, Horton.
정글엔 질서가 있다고
If you want to remain a part of it, l recommend you follow them.
쫓겨나기 싫으면 너도 질서를 지켜
Have a nice day.
그럼 난 가볼게
All right, then, I'll take that under advisement.
알았어 충고 고려해볼게
Certainly appreciate your input.
어든 고마워
I don't understand. I know I heard you.
이상하네 확실히 들었는데
It was as plain as the nose on my face.
내 귀로 분명 들었어
That's it. Maybe you can't hear me.
맞아 내 말이 안 들릴지 몰라
Of course! Your ears must be tiny. I need to speak up.
귀도 작을 테니까! 크게 말해봐야지!
Hello!
이봐요!
Now some people out there, l think l know whe,
여러분도 까칠한 캠거루처럼
may find they agree with that sour Kangaroo.
호튼을 못 믿으시나요?
"There can't really be people as small as a mite."
먼지만큼 작은 사람은 없다고?
Well, there can, and there are, because Horton was right.
아뇨, 실은 있답니다 호튼이 옮았어요
Hello!
이봐요!
That single "hello" traveled all the way down
티끌에 대고 외친 그 소린
to the speck, through the clouds, until it found a small town.
구름을 돌고 한 작은 마을에 당았죠
A town known as Whoville, for there lived the Whos,
누군가 사는 누군가 마을에
feeling happy and safe, knowing only good news,
이들은 늘 행복하고 태평했죠
unaware that their world was a speck ona clover,
자기들 세상이 작은 클로내 위에
unaware that the sweet life they knew might be over.
위태롭게 존재하는 줄도 모른 채
-Over! -Under!
- 위! - 아래!
The Mayor of Whoville, aman named McDedd,
누군가 마을의 시장 맥다드는
was devoted and fair and a little bit odd.
훌륭한 시장이지만 괴짜였어요
The Mayor and his wife, they had children to spare,
그는 부인과 많은 자녀를 죠
96 daughters, some here and some there.
딸이 자그마치 96명이었어요
96 girls to love, 96 girls to teach,
모두 골고루 사랑하고 가르치려면
but the Mayor had only a few seconds for each.
한 명당 몇 초씩밖에 볼 수 없었죠
Daddy, I got better than best on my Who-story test.
누군가 역사 시험 1등 했어요!
Who-story. l remember it well.
역시 년 날 닮았어
That's one of my girls.
잘했다
-Hildy's been using my hairbrush! -Holly's been using my hairbrush!
- 휠디가 내 빗 써요! - 홀리가 내 빗 써요!
Look! Over there!
져길 봐!
There. All better.
이제 됐지?
Can I please have a Who-phone, Dad? Everyone else in my class has one.
누구폰 사줘요 내 친구들 다 있어요
Oh, really? Everyone?
정말? 설마!
I will think about it.
생각해보마
Daddy, look! Daddy, look!
아빠, 봐요!
Toof.
이파
It's a "T-H", sweetheart. It's "tooth."
이빨이야, 이빨
In Whoville tradition, unlike yours or mine,
누군가 마을에선
the Mayor's oldest is next in the Mayoral line.
시장의 맡이가 시장 자릴 물려받죠
And whe was the oldest? To lead and stand tall?
이중 맡이는 누굴까요?
lt was JoJo, his son, the smallest Whe of all.
상꼬맹이 외아들 조조랍니다
So, JoJo, what's shaking? What's happening? What's the word?
조조, 별일 없니? 요즘 어때? 재미 좋아?
Now, to you or to me, it's abundantly clear
여러분도 눈치채셨겠지만
that JoJo did not want his father’s career.
조조는 시장이 되기 싫었어요
But the Mayor pressed forward, completely deluded,
그걸 모르는 안 늘 혼자 오내했고
while JoJo just sat there in silence and broeded.
조조는 말 없이 뚱하게 있곤 했죠
Oh, JoJo!
조조!
-Hey, why does he get more time? -That's not fair.
- 왜 조조하곤 오래 얘기해요? - 불공평해요
Son! Hey!
아들아!
And why didn't he speak?
왜 조조는 침묵할까요?
Well, 1 think that the lad was afraid if he did, he might let down his dad.
말을 하면 아빠가 실망할까 봐 그렇겠죠
You know what's awesome?
멋지지 않니?
This is awesome.
이 초상화들!
Just look at the men and women hanging on these walls.
벽에 걸린 액자 속의 이 얼굴들을 봐
You, my boy, are part of a family legacy that spans centuries.
조조, 년 이 수백 년 된 전통의 일부야
You know what? Your grandfather was Mayor of Whoville,
네 할아네진 누군가 마을의 시장이셨어
and your great-grandmother, that's right,
그리고 네 증조할머니도 그래, 맞아!
all the way down to your
우리 가문의 혈통은
great-great-great-great-not-so-great-
위대한 조상의 조상의 조상의.…… 건너뛰고
great-great-great-great-great-great- great-great-great-great-
조상의 조상의 조상의 조상의 조상의 조상의
grandfather.
원시 조상까지 올라가!
Someday I hope to join them.
나도 이 위대한 전통에
Be one of the greats.
언젠간 끼겠지
I tell you, JoJo, there is nothing like being Mayor.
시장만큼 보람 있는 직업은 없어
I get to sign resolutions, approve ordinances, submit budgets,
법령에 서명하고 예산을 제출하고
and in the Edible Parade, I'm the one sitting on top of the giant meatball.
먹거리 퍼레이드 땐 대형 붕어빵 위에 앉지
Someday, that can be you, too, JoJo.
언젠간 너도 그 일을 하게 될 거야
Someday you'll be the one wearing the Mayoral Crest.
언젠간 시장의 문장도 달게 되겠지
You just... You just need to...
네게 필요한 건 단지.…
You know what I mean?
내 말 뜻 알지?
Okay. Good chat.
그래 대화 즐거웠다!
I'm glad that we had this talk
정말로 유익한 대화였어
that I'm continuing now by myself. Good.
또 나 혼자 떠들었어도 좋아
There. That ought to be comfy.
자, 이제 편하지?
Nothing wrong with this, Morton. Nothing wrong with this.
휴식은 좋은 거야, 모튼 정말 좋은 거야
Just you, me and the speck, shooting the breeze.
우리 셋만의 오봇한 대화!
We're a club. We're a group. We can take a vote on the issues.
클럽 만들까? 폼 잡고 회의도 하고
We can be a secret society that controls the balance of power in the world.
사회 정의를 위해 비밀 조직도 만들고!
-Horton. -And no one else can join,
- 호튼 - 당원은
unless they wear funny hats.
비호감 모자를 써야 돼!
Listen, Horton!
이봐, 호튼!
The Chair recognizes Brother Morton.
모튼 당원, 발언하시오
lam really happy you found this speck and all,
이 티글을 발견한 건 축하하지만
but you might want to think about keeping it to yourself.
소문은 안 내는 게 좋을 것 같아
What? Why?
뭐? 왜?
Well, you're talking to a clover. That doesn't look good.
클로태랑 대화하는 거 좀 오싸
You know what doesn't look good?
말이 심하다
You talking about the speck like the speck isn't even there.
티끌이 듣는데 그런 소릴 해?
The speck never said anything bad about you.
티글은 네 흉본 적 없어
But, hey! Good luck with your illusion of superiority.
너만 잘났다는 착각을 배려
You know, the speck can think anything it wants about me. It's a speck.
그깐 티끌 화내든 말든 관심 없어
I see what's going on here.
알았다 질투하는 거지?
Morton, no matter how tight the speck and I get,
내가 티끌과 아무리 친해도
the speck could never replace you.
티끌이 널 대신할 순 없어
I'm only sad that I would have to explain that, at this point.
그걸 꼭 말해야 아냐?
Well, that's awesome, Horton. That really helps.
고마, 호튼 위안이 되네
Just try to keep this to yourself.
어든 티끌 얘긴 하지 마
I'll see you later. Try.
간다 내 말 명심해
Hey, Horton! What you got there?
호튼, 그게 뭐예요?
What? Nothing!
뭐? 아냐!
We're not doing anything.
우리 아무것도 안 했어
-We're totally alone. -Who's "we"?
- 우린.… 아니, 난.… - '우리' 라뇨?
“We"? What? "We"? Did I say that? I just... Oh.
뭐? 내가 '우리' 랬어?
No, I would never say that, because that would imply that
그런 말 안 했어
I was with someone, and not alone.
옆에 아무도 없어
Okay, seriously, you can't tell anybody. I mean it.
이 얘기 소문 내지 마
If anybody finds out about this, it could be very, very bad.
누가 알게 되면 큰 문제가 생겨
I'm not sure why.
진 모르지만
We won't tell anyone.
말 안 할게요
And if we do, we'll tell them not to tell anyone.
말하더라도 비밀 지키라고 할게요
Perfect!
고마워!
Okay, I'm taking a bath, right,
난 더워서
‘cause my skin gets kind of dry and a little bit ashy.
목욕을 하고 있었어
While Horton came clean about the speck that he'd found
호튼이 티글을 구한 얘길
and how he had saved it when it nearly drowned,
신나게 떠들 동안
the Mayor set off on his morning commute
출근하던 시장은
and noticed things weren't quite the same on his route.
뭔가 이상함을 느껴
But please don't blame Horton, for he didn't know that a small bump above...
호튼은 몰랐어요 그의 작은 동작에.…
..and I dove in the water like this!
난 물에 뛰어들었지!
.. was a big bump below.
.…밑에선 지진이 난다는 걸
Hey, Joe, don't work too hard.
조, 쉬면서 해요!
These luxury condos, they don't build themselves.
이 럭셔리 콘도가 저절로 지어지나?
Hey, look at that! I guess they do build themselves.
저것 봐! 저절로 지어지네!
Okay, that happened.
세상엔 별일도 많아
Now, the Mayor knew it was his job to convey the unusual things
이상한 일은 시의회에 보고해야 되지만
that he'd noticed that day, but there was one problem.
그러기엔 문제가 좀 있었습니다
-You're late. -Thank you, Miss Yelp.
- 늦으셨네요 - 고마워
. nothing in Whoeville had ever gone wrong.
누군가 마을은 늘 완벽했죠
We have all that we need. We need all that we've got.
우린 행복하다
We like it in Whoville. We like it a lot!
누군가 마을은 완벽한 지상 낙원이다!
We're all very busy with the Who-Centennial coming up,
마을 100주년 기념 행사로 바쁘니
so let's bring this meeting to order.
빨리 회의 시작합시다
Mr. Mayor, I presume you have some good news for us.
시장, 오늘도 좋은 소식뿐이겠죠?
Well, it's news.
소식은 있는데
I don't know if we need to go labeling it “good" or "bad" or anything like that.
좋은 건지 나쁜 건진 모르겠네요
The thing is, I have noticed some odd goings-on in Whoville lately.
실은 마을에 이상한 일이 생기고 있어요
Good "odd goings-on"?
좋은 이상한 일들?
Well, you know, tremors, clouds swirling in the sky.
땅과 구름이 흔들려요
And it seems to me, just to be safe,
안전을 위해
we might want to consider postponing the Who-Centennial.
100주년 행사 연기를 고려하는 게.…
Consider what?
뭘 고려해요?
Postponing the Who-Centennial.
연기를.…
What? Speak up, man!
크게 말해요!
Postponing the Who-Centennial! All right?
100주년 행사를 연기하자고요!
We are about to celebrate 100 years of Whoville happiness and harmony,
행복했던 지난 100년을 기념하는 건데
and you want to postpone the celebration?
그 행사를 연기하자고?
Well, what if Whoville’s not safe?
사고 나면요?
Nothing ever goes wrong in Whoville,
이 마을에 사고는 없소
never has and never will, you blathering boob!
과거에도, 미래에도! 찌질이 바보!
The Who-Centennial will proceed as planned!
행사는 예정대로 진행될 거요
The Mayor was merely being an idiot.
멍청한 시장 말 무시해요
It will be all smiles from now on.
이젠 모두 웃을 일뿐이오
That hurt!
아파!
Girl, got 15,000 friends already.
난 일촌이 만 5천 명이에요
What? What do you mean, it don't look like me?
사진이 안 닮다뇨?
That looks just like me 10 years ago. Wait a minute. Hold on for a second.
내 사진 맞아요 10년 전 거지만, 잠깐만요
Treats me like an idiot. 1 am not an idiot.
찌질이 바보? 난 바보가 아냐
Do I look like an idiot?
내가 바보 같아?
-You don't want me to answer that. -l am not an idiot.
- 차마 대답 못하겠네요 - 난 바보가 아냐
Has the nerve to call me a boob? I would never call somebody a boob.
감히 날 찌질이라고? 사돈 남 말하네
He's a boob! Look at you.
밥맛!
Yuck!
엑!
Look at your face.
머리에 이거 한방 맞으면 꼴 좋을 거다!
Whoa! Whoa.
아야!
-Thank you, Miss Yelp. -You're welcome.
- 고마워, 엘프 양 - 뭘요
Hello?
여보세요?
Who said that? Back off! I'll punch you!
물러서! 까불면 맞는다!
Who's there?
누구세요?
This is the Mayor.
난 시장인데?
The Mayor? The Mayor!
시장님? 시장님!
I'm talking to the Mayor!
시장님이래!
I knew it. I knew it. I knew it. I knew there was life on this speck.
역시 이 티끌 속엔 누가 살고 있었어
“This speck"? What speck?
"티끌'? 티끌이라뇨?
Well, I don't exactly know how to tell you this, but...
뭐라 말해야 될지 모르겠지만
You're living on a speck.
당신은 티끌 위에 살아요
Well, l hate to disagree with you, O voice from the drainpipe,
농담하지 마쇼 파이프 속의 목소리 씨
but I live in Whoville.
여긴 누군가 마을이오
Well, then, Whoville's a speck.
티끌 속의 마을이죠
Right.
그래요?
Okay, seriously, who is this?
당신 대체 누구야?
Is this Burt from accounting?
경리과의 버트인가?
No. This is Horton. I'm an elephant.
아뇨 코끼리 호튼인데요
Okay, “Horton.”
그래요, 호튼
Fake name. Where are you?
속을 줄 알고? 당신 어도?
Well, from where you're standing, f guess I'm in the sky.
당신 있는 곳에서 보면 하늘에 있죠
Compared to you, I'm enormous.
당신과 비교하면 난 엄청 커요
Which is saying something, because I've slimmed down quite a bit.
수영으로 살 쁜데도
Your whole world fits on a flower in my world.
당신의 우주는 꽃 한송이 크기죠
Oh, man, this is even pushing it for you, Burt.
농담이 너무 심하군, 버트
Don't believe me? Watch what happens when I put you in the shade.
꽃을 그늘에 놓을 테니 잘 봐요
This is absolutely impossible...
그런 말도 안 되는.
Dark.
어두웠다
Light.
밝았다
Light. Dark, light, dark, light, dark, light, dark.
밝았다, 어두웠다, 밝았다, 어두웠다
Light!
밝았다!
Don't you see?
이제 알겠죠?
We're in the middle of some kind of - - amazing cosmic convergence.
우린 우주의 기적을 체험하고 있어요
Two vastly different worlds, miraculously crossing paths!
전혀 다른 두 세계가 만난 거라고요!
Mine, colossal! Yours, miniscule.
조대형 세계와 조소형 세계가
Yet somehow we've managed to make contact.
우연히 접선한 거죠
if you think about it, it's pretty amazing.
생각해봐요 놀랍지 않아요?
Is everything okay down there?
그 밑에 별일 없어요?
I don't know. You tell me. You're the one holding the speck.
난 모르지 티끌은 당신 손에 있으니
I'm the one holding the speck.
티끌은 내 손에 있다?
Don't you worry, Mr. Mayor.
걱정 마세요, 시장님
Hold, please!
잠깐만!
What did all of this mean? The Mayor hadn't a clue.
머리가 혼란스러운 시장은
So he ran to the office of Dr. Larue, the brainiest brain on the staff at Whe U.
누군가 대학의 브레인 라루 박사를 찾아갔죠
Dr. Larue!
라루 박사!
This is crazy.
난감하네
Mr. Mayor.
시장님
How may I be of assistance?
무슨 일이세요?
I don't know. Hey, you know, I was just wondering
그게 말이에요
if our world were, say, a tiny speck floating through space,
혹시 우리가 사는 세계가 작은 티끌이라면
how would we know?
그걸 어떻게 알 수 있죠?
Well, why would you ask something like that?
그런 걸 왜 묻죠?
No reason. No reason at all. I don't even remember.
나도 몰라요, 그냥.…
Yes, 1 do. You know what?
아니, 실은
Some guy was talking to me.
누군가가 내게 말을 해왔소
Not an elephant in the sky. A guy on the ground.
하늘의 코끼리랑 애기한 건 절대 아니고
There would be several ramifications.
이변이 생기겠죠
Good ramifications?
좋은 이변인가요?
A tiny speck?
작은 티끌이랬죠?
Yeah. Tiny speck.
그래요, 작은 티끌
Floating around.
공중을 떠도는.
Well, we'd have inexplicable tremors, dramatic changes in the weather,
이유 모를 지진과 기후 변화가 있겠죠
and if we didn't eventually achieve some sort of stability,
상황을 안정되게 바꾸지 않으면
our world would be destroyed!
우리의 세계는 파멸될 겁니다!
Destroyed? Destroyed. Oh, destroyed.
파멸? 파멸...
Horton!
호튼!
No, this is Benny.
아뇨 난 베니인데요
Horton is busy right now.
호튼은 지금 바빠요
No. I'm joking.
농담이에요
That's me.
나예요
We're doomed.
우린 끝이군
Listen, Horton, turns out I need your help a little bit.
호튼, 자네 도움이 필요할 것 같네
Apparently, if that speck keeps moving around,
티끌이 계속 떠다니면
our whole world could be obliterated.
우리 세계는 위혐해
Sol need you to find us Whos a safer, more stable home,
자네가 우릴 안전한 곳으로 옮겨주게
and fast.
즉시!
No problem, Mr. Mayor. Let's see...
그야 춤죠, 시장님 어디 보자.…
Wow, that's a nice view.
와, 여기 경치 멋지네!
Hello. Is everything okay?
아무 일 없나?
What's going on up there?
무슨 일이야?
This entire jungle is a house of death!
이 정글 전체가 공포의 도가니예요!
Oh, wait. There's a good spot.
잠깐 좋은 데 있어요
And it's then Horten saw at the top of Mount Nool,
그때 눌루랄라 산이 보였어요
a small cave that looked peaceful and quiet and coal,
산꼭대기의 평화로운 동굴엔
where a sunflower grew proud and tall from the ground.
멋진 해바라기가 피어 있었죠
There, he knew every Whe would be safe, would be sound.
그곳이라면 분명 안전할 거예요
I found it, Mayor. The perfect place.
찾았어요, 시장님 완벽한 장소를!
Right up there,
저기예요
-on the top of Mount Neal. -Mr. Mayor?
-산위의.… - 시장님
l wish you could...
.…동굴이오
Shiny.
광을 잘 냈네
The Who-Centennial Committee is waiting for you
위원회에서 퍼레이드 때 쓸
to look over the giant meatball for the Edible Parade.
초대형 붕어빵을 점검하시랍니다
And then you're due at the dentist for your Who-root canal.
오후엔 치과에 가셔야 돼요
You know, sticking "Who" in front of everything doesn't make it hurt less.
치과에 가느니 충치를 않는 게 나아
Just wastes time!
시간 낭비라고!
I don't want to go.
치과엔 안 가!
Listen, Horton, I've gotta go.
호튼, 가야겠어
Apparently, there's a problem with the giant meatball.
붕어빵이 잘못됐대
You just take care of that meatball, sir, and leave the freaking out to me.
붕어빵이나 신경 써요 걱정은 내게 맡기고
So then Horton began his long, perilous trek,
호튼은 티끌을 구하기 위해
determined to save the small world on the speck.
멀고 힘든 여행을 시작했죠
Horton was faithful and stalwart and kind.
그는 성실하고 용감했어요
I got you.
잡았다
He was a brave here...
그는 영웅이었죠
I'll protect you!
나만 믿어
.at least in his mind.
마음만은요
We must become invisible. Travel silently.
조용히 움직여야 돼
For there are forces that would seek to destroy us.
강호엔 우릴 노리는 적이 많다
So you think you can sneak up on me, huh?
감히 나한테 덤벼?
It is clear that you are no match for my technique.
년 내 맞수가 못 돼
I see you have mastered the way of the snapping branch. Watch me tumble!
빵싸대기 권법을 쓰다니! 구르기를 주마!
Morton Mouse, go!
모튼 검객 출동!
You are fast, Horton, but the Kangaroo has monkeys.
원숭이 요괴들은 내공이 대단해!
I will make monkeys of these monkeys. It is their destiny.
염려 마 다 날려태릴 테니!
More clover!
클로태 장풍!
Horton is the greatest hero of them all!
중원의 절대 고수 호튼!
-Horton! -Morton!
- 호튼! - 모튼!
Go!
출동!
But Mount Nool is that way.
산은 저쪽이야!
To the top of Mount Nool! As fast as lightning! Away, I go.
눌루랄라 산을 향해 바람처럼 간다!
Sorry, little fellow.
미안해, 꼬마
You'll be fine. Just think healing thoughts.
곧 괜찮을 거야 정신력으로 이겨내
-Horton! Look! -Horton! Look, look, look!
- 호튼, 저기 좀 봐요! - 호튼, 봐요
We've all got our own clovers with worlds on them!
우리 클로내에도 세상이 있어요!
Yeah.
네
In my world, everyone's a pony,
내 클로내엔 조랑말이 살아요
and they all eat rainbows and poop butterflies.
무지개를 먹고 나비 응가를 싸는
That's beautiful, Katie.
근사하네, 케이티
In a really weird way.
좀 찜찜하지만
My world is called Jessica-land, and everyone worships Queen Jessica
내 세상은 제시카 랜드예요
because Jessica is so beautiful.
내가 왕짱이에요
Jessica, that was awesome.
제시카 완전 부럽다.…
-Rudy! -Mom, be careful!
- 루디! - 엄마, 조심해요
My best friend Thidwick lives on that.
내 친구 다쳐요!
Rudy, no one lives on this. It's not possible.
클로버 위엔 아무도 안 산다니까!
That Horton is a menace.
못된 호튼 녀석
Mom, Mom! Please, you're so weird. Don't do this to me.
엄마, 그러지 마요
Honey, go to your room.
방에 들어가
Horton!
호튼!
It's good!
나이스 키!
What do you think you're doing?
뭐 하는 거야?
You guys with worlds are in trouble!
너희들 큰일났다
-Have you forgotten what we discussed? -Oh, no. I'm an elephant,
- 내 충고 잊었니? - 코끼리는
and elephants never forget. It's a curse, really.
기억력이 좋아
l remember I was on my head, and you said “Humpf,"
그래서 때론 괴롭지
and I looked up, and you said, “What are you doing?"
년 날 비웃으면서 말했어 “뭐해?'
And I said the thing about the speck.
난 티끌 얘길 했고
Then you pulled my ears and you poked me in the forehead...
년 내 귀를 당겼지
-Horton! -Well, you did.
- 호튼! - 맞잖아
Give me that clover, Horton. Now!
클로내 줘, 호튼 어서!
No.
싫어
No?
싫다고?
Yeah.
그래
Are you sure you want to fight this fight, Horton?
정말 나랑 싸우겠다는 거야?
Because I promise you it will get very ugly, very fast.
내 주먹 작렬하면 년 한방에 끝나
And you need to ask yourself,
신중히 생각해
“Dol really want to put myself through all this?
"이게 정말 후회 없는 선택일까?'
“For a clover?”
"고작 티끌 때문에?'
Take it from me, Horton.
충고할 때 들어
You don't.
싫어?
So hand it over!
그거 내나!
No! I can't give it to you.
싫어 절대 못 내뇌
There are people on this speck.
여긴 사람이 살아
Granted, they're very small people,
크기가 아무리 작아도
but a person's a person, no matter how small.
생명은 소중한 거야
You just crossed the line, Horton, and I'm gonna make you pay.
년 날 무시했어 그 대가를 치러야 돼
That Horton is a menace.
호튼은 골첫거리야
He has those kids using their imaginations.
애들의 상상력을 이용하고 있어
It's sick.
역겨워
All right, gotta get this speck up to the top of Mount Nool, ASAP,
이걸 산으로 옮겨야 돼 최대한 신속히!
whatever that means. Probably, “Act Swiftly, Awesome Pachyderm.”
여기서 '신속' 은 "신나게 속사포처럼"!
I mean, how hard can that be?
힘들 거 없어
It's just a straight plummet to certain death.
기껏해야 사망으로 곧장 직행이겠지
This looks kind of precarious.
흔들 다리 근사하네 스릴 있고
Well, no need to worry.
걱정할 거 없어
Obviously, when they build a bridge like this,
설마 다리를 만들 때
they take into account that elephants will be crossing here.
코끼리 건너는 거 예상 안 했겠어?
All right. Feels good. I'll just get the feel of it!
좋아, 감이 좋군 일단 한번 감을 보고.
That's true.
사실이야
Oh, God.
맘소사
Hello. And how are we today, Mr. Mayor?
오셨군요 오랜만이에요, 시장님
Say, "Ah."
"아' 하세요
Rinse, please.
행구세요
I think a few of these boards could stand to be replaced.
나무판들 상태가 대략 난감이군
I just need to think light. I'm light as a feather.
최면을 걸자 "난 깃털처럼 가벼'
Heavy feather.
저질 깃털
Okay, this will just pinch a little.
자, 약간 따끔할 겁니다
I'm lighter than a feather. What's lighter than a feather?
난 깃털보다 가바 더 가벼운 게 뭐지?
Air! There's nothing lighter. So it stands to reason
공기가 세상에서 제일 가법지
that the more air I have,
그러니까 공기를 많이 마실수록
the lighter I'll be.
내 몸은 가녀워져!
Next, please.
다음 환자!
All right, that was absolutely terrifying.
오늘 완젼 모냥 빠지네
If I just pull myself up!
용기를 잃지 말자!
Try not to panic.
마음을 강하게 먹어
That could've been a disaster.
일단 위기는 벗어났고!
Wow. I feel really good right now. Maybe it's my new sense of purpose.
기운이 급 촛아나네 이래서 목적의식이 필요해
All right.
좋아
Hey, JoJo! I need your help. Can you help me?
조조, 날 좀 도와줄래?
Okay, great. Okay. First, ! need you to go to the girls' room.
좋아, 일단 동생들 침실로 가서
Take down Hanna's china doll collection and then...
도자기 인형 내려놓고.…
Stop looking at my arm.
팔 보지 마
Put away Holly's light bulb collection, and then...
홀리가 수집한 전구와
You know what? Just take care of anything that might break or shatter.
깨질 것들 다 치워
Okay, take a good long look.
그래, 실컷 쳐다봐
Got it? Thanks, JoJo!
됐지? 고맘다, 조조!
Here. And... Take that. And...
어디 보자.…
Hi. You're home late.
퇴근이 늦었네요
Sorry, hon. I was just having some dental work done on my arm.
미안해, 여보 충치 치료받았어, 팔뚝에
So, what was...
네?
Ned!
여보!
What are you doing?
지금 뭐 해요?
What do you mean?
내가 뭘?
Well, I'm no detective, Ned, but you are hanging from the chandelier.
상들리에에 매달려 있잖아요
I just thought it might look better
잘때
somewhere it can't fall on us and crush us in our sleep.
머리에 떨어지면 위험할까 봐
What is going on?
무슨 일이에요?
Hey, hon,
혹시 누가
did you ever get the feeling that you were being watched?
당신을 지켜본단 느낌 받은 적 없어?
Yeah, sure. I suppose.
네, 있죠 가끔은요
And then you get the feeling that maybe that thing watching you is
당신을 지켜보는 게 거대한 코끼리라는 느낌은
a giant elephant?
없었어?
And you know how you get that weird feeling
우리가 살고 있는 세상은
that your world is actually a tiny speck?
티끌에 불과하단 느낌
And that the elephant that I talked about earlier is carrying it around on a flower.
그 티끌이 묻은 꽃을 코끼리가 들고 있단 느낌
And you realize that if you tell anybody, they'd think you were crazy.
그걸 말하면 다들 미쳤다고 하겠지만
But you still feel a responsibility to keep everyone safe.
모두를 위해서 말해야 할 것 같은 느낌!
You know that feeling?
그 느낌 알아?
You know, I'm gonna have to say no.
근데 잘 모르겠어요
Do you know that feeling?
당신은 알아요?
No.
아니!
Yawn. Wow. I am beat. Time to hit the hay, I guess.
무지 피곤하네 그만 잡시다
Sweetheart, I know you're under a lot of stress,
당신, 스트레스 많은 거 알아요
and if you're seeing elephants and flowers, then fine.
코끼리와 꽃의 환상을 볼 수도 있죠
Just don't tell anyone else that story, okay?
남들한테 애기만 하지 마요
And remember, it's not the end of the world.
실망 마요 세상이 끝난 것처럼
“The end of the world.”
세상이 끝나?
Horton to Mayor. Horton to Mayor. Come in, Mayor. Over.
여긴 호튼 시장님 나와라, 오너
Horton?
호튼?
I get terrible reception here.
수신 상태가 나빠
How about this? If l get up real close, can you read me?
지금은요? 이젠 잘 들리세요?
Yep! Roger that.
그래, 잘 들려!
Are we at that safe place yet?
안전한 데로 왔나?
Almost. I'm pretty sure the worst part's over.
거의요 위험한 덴 벗어났죠
This is your elephant speaking.
여긴 코끼리 기장!
Just sit back, enjoy the ride, and we'll have you to Mount Nool in no time.
잠시후 눌루랄라 산에 도착합니다
No, you can't have ice cream for breakfast.
아침엔 아이스크림 안 돼
-Please.
- 엄마
Who's that?
누구예요?
Is there someone else there?
딴사람도 있어요?
Well, that's my wife and kids.
내 아내와 애들이야
You have a family.
가족이 있군요
I do, indeed. A beautiful wife, 96 daughters, and one son.
있지, 아름다운 아내와 딸 96명, 아들 1명
Oh, busy guy.
바쁘시겠네
And we all share one bathroom. You know how that is.
화장실은 딸랑 한 개야
Yeah. Don't I know it.
많이 힘드시겠네
Bathroom?
화장실?
-Ned! -What?
- 네드! - 왜?
Sweetheart, you know you're on the roof, right?
거기 지붕 위라는 거 알죠?
-Please, Mom. -What's that?
- 엄마 - 가서 자
No, you need to go to bed. Daddy's having a breakdown.
안 신경 과민이셔
Ned, what are you up to now?
대체 왜 그래요?
I was just about to put the kids to bed when I got off the roof.
지금 내려가서 애들 재우려던 참이야
And that's what happened. Right.
걱정 마, 내려갈게
-Daddy? -Yes.
- 아빠? - 왜?
-Can I have a glass of water? -Of course.
- 물 한잔만 주실래요? - 그래
-Me, too. -Me, three.
- 나도요!
Me, 28.
나도요
Okay.
알았다
Hey, JoJo!
조조!
A lot of liquid. A lot of liquid. Just the person I wanted to see.
아빠 재주 좋지? 마침 잘 만났다
Yeah, I realize that we have not been seeing eye-to-eye lately,
요즘 너랑 얼굴 맞대고 대화를 못했어
and most of it is my fault.
다 내 잘못이지
It's true.
그래
You know what I've been trying to do?
네게 사과할 게 있어
I have been trying to impose my vision of your future on you.
내 뒤를 이으라고 강요했던 거
Let me make this perfectly clear.
네 미래는 네 거야
JoJo, you can be whatever kind of Mayor you want to be.
조조, 네가 되고 싶은 시장이 되거라
Hands-on, strong and silent, outspoken, it's up to you.
어떤 시장이 되든 네 맘이야
Well, good. I feel so much better.
이젠 내 마음이 편하구나
lam expecting big things from you, young man. Big things.
난 너에게 엄청 기대가 크단다!
All right. Good night.
잘 자라
Good stuff. Good talk.
대화 즐거웠다
Then JoJo snuck out, feeling lonely and sad,
울적해진 조조는 집을 나왔죠
and tragically misunderstood by his dad.
아빠에게 더욱 실망한 채
And where was he going at such a late hour?
이 밤중에 그가 간 곳은
Up te Whoville's abandoned Star-Studying Tower,
폐허가 된 천문 관측대였어요
a place where the boy felt contented, free.
거기선 편하고 자유로웠죠
A place he could be what he wanted te be.
누구의 간섭도 없었으니까요
And what was inside there, I'd say if 1 could.
그곳엔 놀라운 비밀이 있었죠
Can I come out now, Mom?
나가도 돼요?
No, Rudy. Stay in your room.
안돼 방 안에 있어
-But, Mom... -Stay inside.
- 하지만 엄마.… - 나오지 마
Mr. Vladikoff?
블래디코프?
Eating. Go.
식사 중야 꺼져!
Yes, l realize you're busy, but I need your help.
바쁜 건 알지만 도움이 필요해서요
It's Horton.
코끼리 호튼이
He's become obsessed with a clover.
클로태에 미쳤어요
And he actually thinks there are little people on it.
그 속에 작은 사람들이 산대요
I want that clover destroyed.
클로태를 없애쥐요
Sure. What a big deal this is for you, bro.
그래, 심각한 문제군 너한텐!
I'd do it myself, but being a lady, I prefer not to get my hands dirty.
내가 하고 싶지만 숙녀가 피볼 순 없잖아요?
But I hear you have no problem with that.
당신이 그런 일 프로라던데?
No.
맞아
No problem. Easy peazy.
그런 일쯤은 식은 죽 먹기지
But I will only do this for a price.
대신 수고비가 좀 비싸
In exchange for a brand new pair of...
병아리 한 쌍을 줘
No.
아니
This little kangaroo.
요 새끼 캠거루
-Mom! -Quiet, Rudy. Mommy's thinking it over.
- 엄마! - 조용히 해, 생각 좀 해보게
Well, thanks, but on second thought,
고맘지만 생각해보니
I think I'm going to have the Wickersham brothers
위커샘 형제가 더 잘할 것 같네요
Yeah, of course, Wickersham. I mean, they're a classy operation.
그래 개들 솜씨 예술이지
You know, they do... Wait! No! You can't go with Wickersham!
안돼! 개들한텐 가지 마!
No, no, no, the Wickershams would be perfect for this job.
아니 위커샘 형제가 딱이네요
But they're monkeys! Is not scary!
원숭이 따위 아무도 겁 안 내!
Thanks, anyway. Maybe next time.
어펄든 고마웠어요 다음에 올게요
Wait!
잠깐!
Here is what I will do to precious clover.
그 클로너는 나한테 맡겨
I will take it, I will crush it,
내가 뱃어서 뭉개태릴게
and I will devour it.
썸어 삼켜태릴게
Bigger than it look.
보기보다 크네
One second.
잠깐만
Holy moly.
이런, 썩을!
Then I regurgitate it.
토해내서
Then I'm going to devour it second time!
또 한번 썸어 삼켜태릴게
So, two times devoured.
두번 썸어 삼키는 거지
Sounds nice, but I think I'll talk to the Wickershams.
솔깃은 한데 위커샘 형제가 낮겠어요
Wait!
잠깐! 본론을 들어보셔
Here is best part.
보수는
I do all gratis.
안 받을게
That's free, bro.
공짜로 해준다고
What do you think?
어떠셔?
Deal.
콜!
Yes! Score. Thanking you. You won't regret.
좋았어, 고마워! 절대 후회 안 할 거야
Mayor!
시장님!
Open up, Mr. Mayor! Mr. Mayor!
문 여세요, 시장님!
It's snowing! In the summer!
눈이 와요 한여름인데!
Yes. Yes, it is.
정말이네 눈이 와!
It's a dramatic change in the weather,
기후가 급변했어요
as if we were a speck, floating through space.
세상이 티글인 듯
I don't know how you knew, but somehow you did,
어떻게 이걸 미리 예측하셨죠?
and Whoville is headed for disaster.
누군가 마을은 이제 곧 파멸한대요
Horton.
호튼
What?
네?
Nothing. I'm on it.
아니오 내게 맡겨요
It's up to us to save the people of Whoville.
마을은 우리가 지켜야 돼요
You're small, but there are a lot of you!
끝도 없이 나오는군
That's it.
그래
Okay, anybody else?
또 남았니?
Good.
눈이다!
No, no. No enjoyment. This is not fun. It is a sign of doom!
그만 해, 신날 거 없어 이건 재앙의 신호야!
Aw, sweetie, that's...
헤디, 예쁘고.
No, no, no! Danger! Danger!
안돼 위험해, 위험해!
Stop having fun immediately!
그만 놀고 당장 들어가!
This is dangerous! Okay!
위혐하대도! 알았어!
Stop it!
멈춰!
Horton!
호튼!
Hey, Mayor.
시장님
We're in big trouble down here.
큰 문제가 생겼네
It's happening! It's snowing in the middle of summer.
여름에 눈이 와
It's the end of the world!
드디어 종말이 왔어!
Hold on, Mayor. I think I know what your problem is.
잠깐만요 이유를 알 만하네요
There. That better?
이제 됐죠?
That seems to have worked.
성공한 것 같군
Do I smell peanuts?
땅콩 냄새네?
Yeah, they're my favorite snack, but they tend to linger.
제가 땅콩을 좋아해요 냄새가 오래 남죠
Finwick, no!
핀위, 안 돼!
Hang on, Mr. Mayor. I may have to put up a fight.
곽 잡아요, 시장님 적이 오나 봐요
A frightened elephant can be very dangerous!
난 겁나면 막 떨거든요!
All right! You've called down the thunder, buddy!
그래, 덤벼 너 오늘 잘못 걸렸어!
You hungry for trouble? I'm an “All you can eat" salad bar! Take a bite!
내 얼굴은 겸손해도 성질은 더럽다고, 덤벼!
I hate running.
뛰는 건 질색이야
Morton!
모튼!
Don't do that.
다신 그러지 마
Horton!
호튼!
Horton! There you are!
여기 있었구나!
We got trouble! Wait, stay, wait! Did you hear that?
큰일났어 저 소리 들려?
No, I'm here, okay. Listen. No! Go! Kangaroo has gone nuts, bananas.
내 말 잘 들어 캠거루가 완전 열받았어
She's telling everyone that you should be kicked out of Nool.
널 정글에서 쫓아낸대
She said that? I thought we were her friends.
정말? 친구로 여겼는데
Word is she's gone to Vlad!
블래드를 찾아갔대!
Vlad? Vlad? I know two Vlads.
블래드? 둘 중에 누구?
Is it the bad Vlad or the bunny Vlad that makes the cookies?
악당 블래드? 쿠키 굽는 토끼 블래드?
Yeah, Horton, she's sending you a bunny with cookies.
설마 쿠키 굽는 토끼겠나?
I think we can assume it's the bad Vlad.
당연히 악당 블래드겠지
Yeah, that's a good call.
하긴 그러네
So unless you're cool with giant, razor-sharp claws
크고 사나운 독수리의 날카로운 발톱에
ripping the flesh off your body, I'd get rid of the clover!
기기 싫으면 클로태를 배려!
I can't! promised the Mayor.
안돼 시장님과 약속했어
I meant what I said, and I said what I meant,
난 의리의 사나이야
and an elephant's faithful, 100%.
약속은 100% 지켜
Please. For me, just this once. Be faithful 99% of the time.
날 봐서 이번만은 99%만 지키면 안 될까?
I've never gotten 99% on anything, and I think I'm awesome! So, come on!
뭐든지 12% 부족한 게 좋은 거야
I meant what I said, and I said what I meant.
좀 전에 내가 뭐랬지? “난 약속을.…
I'm not gonna say it.
싫어 말안해
You can do that all day, it's not happening.
쳐다봐라, 말하나
An elephant's faithful, 100%.
……100% 지킨다'
That's right. That's my code, my motto. But thanks for the warning.
맞아, 그게 내 신조야 어든 충고 고마워
Motto. Okay.
신조, 그래
But watch the skies.
하늘이나 조심해
Keep watching the skies!
계속 하늘을 지켜보란 말이야!
Mayor, you need to get everyone underground.
시장님, 모두 지하로 대피시켜요!
Now!
지금 당장요!
1 don't want to sound the alarm,
겁주긴 싫지만
but there's a good possibility we may be attacked
거대한 독수리가
-by a giant carnivorous bird. -What?
- 공격해올지 몰라요 - 뭐?
There's a small chance it could be a bunny with cookies, but ! wouldn't count on it.
쿠키 굽는 토끼일 확률은 거의 없어요
They are formidable.
이들은 강했어
Mayor? Are you there?
시장님? 듣고 있어요?
Yeah. No. That's a great idea. It's just...
좋은 생각이지만
In order to get everyone mobilized, I'd need the okay of the City Council,
주민을 이동시키려면 시의회의 동의가 필요한데
and they never listen to me.
내 말은 안 먹혀
I've been called a boob,
날 찌질이 바보래!
several times. I can't do it!
말해도 소용없어!
You have to talk to them, Mayor! Okay. Listen.
그래도 설득해야죠
Bad Vlad!
악당 블래드다!
That is definitely not a bunny.
토끼는 역시 아니었군
Lost him. Meant to lose him, and I lost him. Good.
성공이야 계획대로 따돌렸어
Is this tree for real? Come on!
이 썩을 나무가!
Hang on, Whoville! This is gonna get rough!
모두 곽 잡아요! 흔들릴 거요!
Now you're going to get it!
년 딱 걸리셨세요!
Get ready for the best!
최후의 일격이다!
Leave me alone!
따라오지 마!
Horton!
호튼!
I just know he's gonna jump out somewhere.
어디선가 나타날 거야
Hello.
이봐요!
Chess mate.
년 끝났어
Now it's time for me to take clover
티끌 속의 생명들을
and crush all the little people on it, who are saying...
깔끔히 작살내주마
Sorry. This is where we get off.
미안한데 이제 작별하자고
Right in the beak!
나 완전 새 됐어!
Cool line. Usually I can't think of those things till later.
애드리브 좋군 학원에서 배웠나?
-Mayor? -Horton.
- 시장님? - 호튼
Are you okay?
괜찮아요?
Well, more or less. What happened? The bird?
괜찮아 새한테 공격받았나?
Yeah, it attacked me. Mayor, your people are in danger.
네, 날 공격했어요 그곳 주민이 위험해요
You know what? I'm gonna do it.
알았어, 전할게
I'm going to go out there and tell them what is going on.
모두에게 이 상황을 말할게
Perfect. Now, quick. Get going.
좋아요 어서 가요
Hey! Mr. Mayor! Something's wrong!
시장, 뭔가 이상해요!
-My basement's in the attic. -The Science Museum is history.
- 집이 뒤집어졌소 - 박물관도요
-The lost and found is missing. -What's going on, Mr. Mayor?
- 분실물 센터도요 - 대체 무슨 일이죠?
I'm declaring a state of emergency!
비상사태를 선포합니다!
Don't worry! Don't worry!
별거 아뇨! 걱정 마요!
The Mayor is just being a moron.
시장은 원래 겁쟁이요
No, wait! Whoville is in terrible danger!
잠깐! 우린 큰 위험에 처했소!
Everyone needs to get down to the underground storage area immediately.
모두 지하 저장실로 즉시 대피해요!
Fine! Fine!
좋소!
Let's do this democratically.
민주적으로 해결합시다
Who wants the joy and glory and festivity
계획대로 100주년 기념일을
of the Who-Centennial to proceed as planned?
즐거운 축제 속에 보내고 싶은 분들?
Yeah!
저요!
And who, like the Mayor,
겁쟁이 시장처럼
thinks it would be better to spend the Who-Centennial
어두컴컴한 지하에서 우울하게 100주년을
in an underground storage area?
보내고 싶은 분들?
Yeah!
저요!
Wait! You've gotta listen to me!
내 말을 들으세요!
Our whole world could explode!
세상이 곧 빵 하고 폭발할지 몰라요!
Much more quickly!
이것보단 빠르게요!
And our world wouldn't make that noise.
소리도 훨씬 크게!
The people have spoken, Mr. Mayor.
주민들의 뜻을 봤잖소
You're finished. No one believes you.
당신은 끝났어 아무도 안 믿어쥐
No one supports you.
당신 편은 없다고
Horton believes me.
호튼은 날 믿어
Horton?
호튼?
Who's Horton?
호튼이 누군데?
Horton is a giant elephant in the sky!
호튼은 하늘에 있는 거대한 코끼리 입니다!
Don't bother looking, he's invisible.
봐도 안 보여요
And he's the one risking his life to get Whoville,
그는 티끌에 불과한 우릴
which, by the way, is a speck on a clover, to safety!
안전한 데로 옮겨주기 위해 목숨을 걸었어요!
I can prove it!
증명하겠소!
Horton's voice comes out of this horn.
여기서 호튼의 음성이 나와요!
Horton!
호튼!
I have all the Whos gathered in town square!
주민들을 광장에 집합시켰어!
Let them know you're there!
자네 목소릴 들려줘!
Gee. This is kind of a high-pressure situation, then.
난감하네 무슨 얘길 하지?
Wow. l am really drawing a blank here.
머릿속이 급 하얘지네
I know!
맞다!
Horton!
호튼!
Horton, we're waiting!
호튼, 뭐 해?
Time to show everyone that you exist,
자네가 진짜 있다는 걸 보여줘
and by extension, what a non-boob I am.
내가 찌질이가 아니라는 것도
Wait!
잠깐만!
Everyone, look at the wind. What do you think that that means?
바람을 봐요 저게 뭘 뜻하겠소?
It means...
저건.…
It means, obviously...
뭘 뜻하냐 하면.…
Let the kite-flying race begin!
연날리기 대회 할 때가 됐다는 거요!
What a burn on you, Horton!
완전 굴욕 모드군, 호튼!
Brain freeze.
골이 빠개지겠네
Give me back my speck!
내 티끌!
Not this time, guy.
이번엔 포기해
lam so sorry that I let you down, but this... This is bigger than me.
당신을 실망시켜 미안해 내 힘으론 어 수 없어
Get the family together and get somewhere safe.
애들과 안전한 데로 피해
I will! l believe you.
알았어요! 난 당신 믿어요
I've got you now, elephant.
년 이제 완전 끝장야, 뚱때!
No, no, no!
안돼!
Mayor?
시장님?
Anybody there?
아무도 없어요?
Hello?
이봐요!
Anyone?
누구 없어요?
But clover by clover by clover, he found
수없는 클로버를 뒤졌지만
that the one he sought for was just not around.
그가 찾는 클로태는 없었습니다
Mayor?
시장님?
Hello?
누구 없어요?
And by noon, poor Horton, more dead than alive,
조죽음이 된 호튼은
had picked, searched and piled up 9,005.
오전 내내 9전 다섯 송이의 클로태를 뒤졌습니다
Hello?
여보세요?
Sorry to bother you,
귀찮게해서 미안해
nobody.
아무도 없군
Knock, knock.
똑똑!
This is where you'd say, "Who's there?"
그럼 대답해야지 "누구세요?'
if there were any Whos there.
누군가 있으면 말이야
Get it? "Whos there.”
웃기지? 나 이러고 있다
All day he looked, looked on and on,
온종일 그는 찾고 또 찾았쇼
until his hope was almost gone.
희망이 거의 사라질 무렵
No, no, no! Please, no!
안돼, 안 돼! 날아가지 마!
This isn't fair!
이럴 순 없어!
But, wait, could this one be the one?
잠깐만 혹시 이게 아닐까?
Was all his searching finally done?
고생한 보람이 있는 걸까?
Ah, yes, for this was the hour.
네, 보람은 있었죠
Horton had found them on the three millionth flower.
3백만 번째에서 결국 찾았거든요
Mayor! Mayor!
시장님!
I found you!
여기 있었군요!
Mayor?
시장님?
Are you there?
듣고 계세요?
Mayor.
시장님
Mayor, are you there?
시장님, 듣고 계세요?
Mayor!
시장님!
Mayor?
시장님?
No, this is Floyd.
아니, 난 플로이드요
Can I take a message?
메시지 전해줄까요?
Mayor! You're okay!
시장님, 무사하군요!
Horton! Horton! Stop! Stop it!
호튼, 흔들려 그만 해!
Sorry.
죄송!
lt must have been rough down there. l can't believe found you.
무사하다니 너무 기뻐서요
You really had me worried.
무지 걱정했어요
Say! The Mayor was right!
시장 말이 옮았어!
Daddy! Daddy! Daddy!
아빠! 아빠! 아빠!
Okay, I'm all right, and so are you.
난 괜찮아 너희도 무사하구나
Citizens of Whoville!
누군가 마을 주민 여러분!
I'd like you to meet our friend Horton.
우리의 친구를 소개하죠 호튼!
He's going to help us!
우릴 도와줄 겁니다
I've got this.
내게 맡겨
This is the Chairman...
난 의장이다
Idiot!
밥맛!
You're finished in this town! Is that understood? Finished.
당신은 끝났어 끝장났다고
You boob!
바보 찌질이!
I'm just joking.
농담한 거예요
Good one.
재밌군
Horton, this is my wife Sally.
내 아내 샐리야
You exist!
반가워요
This means my husband isn't crazy.
내 남편이 미친 게 아니었네?
Hooray!
만세!
And a few of my daughters, Haley, Holly, Hooly, Hilda and Hedy.
내 딸들의 대표 할리, 홀리, 훌리, 힐다, 헤디
-Hi!
- 안녕!
And here is Miss Yelp, my loyal assistant.
내 충실한 비서 엘프 양
-And here's Dr. Larue. -You saved us!
- 라루 박사 - 우릴 구해주셨어요
And Burt from accounting,
경리과의 배트
and Mrs. MeGillicuddy, and Mr. Farfoogan
장다리 가족인 맥길리커디 부인과
from the Clugan Farfoogans,
파푸건 씨
and the old man in the bathtub.
여긴 목간통 노인
Let's not overwhelm the poor fellow.
대충 해뒤요
He's never gonna remember all these names.
다 기억 못해요
Well, I'll try my best.
최대한 기억해볼게요
Sally, Chairman,
샐리, 의장님
Haley, Hooly, Holly, Hilda, Hedy, Miss Yelp,
할리, 홀리, 훌리, 힐다, 헤디 그리고 엘프 양
Dr. Larue, Burt from accounting, Mrs. McGillicuddy, Mr. Farfoogan
라루 박사, 경리과의 버트 맥길리커디 부인, 파푸건 씨
of the Clugan Farfoogans, and wasn't there an old guy in a shower?
그리고 샤워장 노인?
Bathtub.
목간통 노인
-Yeah! -We're all here, Horton,
- 아깝다! - 모두 모였어
and we all believe in you.
우린 모두 자네를 굳게 믿네
Wow. That's awesome.
그거 감동이네요
And it's a responsibility I do not take lightly.
난 이 임무 꼭 완수할 거예요
I promise you a future that is safe, sound and stable.
여러분의 안전한 미래를 약속할게요
We will create a world where every Who is endowed with three inalienable rights,
세 가지 권리도 보장하죠 그 세 가지가 뭔지는
to be determined at a later date.
나도 아직 몰라요
And we will put a speck on Mount Nool before the end of this decade.
10년 안에는 눌루랄라 산에 도착할 거예요
This elephant is crazy! Oh, my goodness.
코끼리가 완전히 미쳤군
I gotta tell everybody. I need to get to the Kangaroo.
빨리 알려야 돼 캠거루 어디?
Wait till they find out about...
이 얘길 들으면.…
You should have been seeing me. I really let elephant have it.
네가 봤어야 돼 완전 작살 내줬어
I chase him, I torment him, I break him into million little elephant pieces.
추격자처럼 집중 공격 혼쓸을 내줬지
It was thing of beauty, really. My best work. Classic Vlad.
예술이었어 내 최고의 작품이었지
And the clover?
클로배는?
Clover is finished! No way in million years Horton find it.
끝장냈지! 절대 못 찾아
Read my beak. Clover is gone forever.
내 부리 잘 봐 클로태는 영원히 사라졌어
I just saw Horton, and he is still talking to that clover!
호튼이 클로내와 애기하는 걸 봤어!
Idiot!
머저리!
Whoa! Come on, I'm your bro! It's me you're talking to. We have history!
이러면 섭하지 우리 한때 좋았잖아
Come on, let's not forget, I did this for free!
공짜로 일해준 거 잊지 마!
What is happening to the jungle of Nool?
눌루랄라 정글이 왜 이렇게 됐지?
There once was a time when people were people
언제부터 하찮은 티글을
and specks were specks.
사람 취급하게 된 거야?
Well, l say, “If you can't see it, hear it or feel it,
안 보이고 안 들리고 안 만져지면
“it doesn't exist!"
없는 거야!
Our way of life is under attack!
우리 삶이 위협받고 있어!
And who is leading that attack? Horton!
누구로부터? 바로 호튼으로부터!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
잠깐, 잠깐만!
Wait a minute! This is Horton we're talking about.
진정들 해 호튼을 몰라서 그래?
You all know him, he wouldn't hurt a fly.
괜 파리 한마리 못 죽여
Except for that fly city he sat on. But he didn't do that on purpose.
파리 굴 깔고 앉은 건 사고였고!
Shut up, mouse!
닥쳐, 생쥐!
That's weird. My brownies are burning. I gotta go!
참, 케이크 다 타겠네 가볼게
Are we going to let troublemakers like Horton poison the minds of our children?
호튼 때문에 애들 다 내리겠어 구경만 할 거야?
Not the children!
그럴 순 없지!
When Horton tells our children about worlds beyond the jungle,
정글 말고 딴 세상이 있단 얘길 들으면
he makes them question authority!
부모를 우습게 알게 돼!
Which leads to defiance! Which leads to anarchy!
그럼 정글은 난장판 무법 천지가 돼!
Yeah! Horton must pay!
놈은 벌 받아야 돼!
It's that speck!
티끌을 없애자!
We have to do something!
뭔가 해야만 돼!
For the children!
애들을 위해!
Are we going to let him get away with this?
녀석이 하는 짓을 이대로 구경만 할 거야?
No!
그건 안 되지!
Let's go!
전진!
Morton! I told you! 100%!
모튼, 봤지? 난 약속을 100% 지켜!
Horton!
호튼!
Morton, pick up your feet! Jeez.
살살 뛰어 땅 꺼질라!
It's not me!
내 발소리 아냐!
I see. It's an angry mob. Sorry, Morton.
그래 성난 폭도들이군
I thought it was you that was making all the...
미안해 난 네 발소리인 줄.…
But it's...
뭐야.…
Oh, darn.
맘소사
Run, Horton!
튀어, 호튼!
There he is!
저기다!
Let's rope him!
맛줄로 묶자!
Let's cage him!
우리에 가두자!
No! No! No!
안돼! 안돼!
Stop!
그만!
Hey, fellas. Good to see you,
안녕 다들 모였네
all at once.
한꺼번에
You look really great as a horde.
겁나 살벌하군
Horton, Horton, Horton,
호튼, 호튼
look at the mess you've created for yourself.
그러게 진작 내 말 듣지
All this hullabaloo over a silly little flower.
꽃 한 송이 때문에 이게 무슨 난리야?
It's a speck.
티끌이야
Right. mean, it's silly, really, all this talk of roping you,
그거 따질 때 아냐 다들 널 발로 묶고
and caging you, and, well, we don't need to go into the details.
우리에 가두라지만 네가 맘을 바꾸면
The point is, this angry mob, all the trouble you're in,
이 화난 군중도 이 곤경도
it can all go away.
벗어날 수 있어
-Really? -Of course.
- 그래? - 물론이지
All you have to do is admit to everyone that there are no little people
그 티끌 속엔 작은 사람이 살지 않는다고
living on that speck.
말만 하면 돼
That you were wrong and I was right.
네 생각이 틀렸고 내 생각이 옮다고
You do that and things can go right back to the way they were.
그렇게만 하면 예전으로 돌아갈 수 있어
But if you don't, you're going to have to pay the price.
그렇지 않으면 년 대가를 치르게 될 거야
So, I just have to say it isn't true?
다 뱅이라고 말해라?
Go ahead. Rope me, cage me. Do whatever you want.
좋아, 묶든지 가두든지 마음대로 해
But there are people on this speck.
여긴 사람들이 살아
And they have a Mayor, who has 96 daughters and one son named JoJo,
시장도 있어 1남 96녀를 가진!
who all share a bathroom, whatever that is,
화장실은 하나야 그게 뭔진 몰라도
and even though you can't hear or see them at all,
들리지 않고 보이지 않아도
a person's a person, no matter how small.
생명은 소중한 거야!
That was beautiful, Horton.
정말 감동적인 얘기군
Rope him! Cage him!
묶어서 가두고
And burn that speck in a pot of boiling Beezlenut oil!
티끌은 태워! 펼펼 끌는 기름 가마솔에!
They don't believe we're here.
우리 존재를 안 믿어요
We've got to make some noise!
소리를 지릅시다!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
우리 여기 있어요! 여기 있어요! 여기 있어요!
Come on!
크게!
-Everybody! -We are here! We are here! We are here!
- 다 함께! - 우리 여기 있어요! 여기 있어요!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
우리 여기 있어요! 여기 있어요! 여기 있어요!
This will teach you not to make up stories about people on specks!
다신 허튼 거짓말 못하게 해주마!
Listen! There they are!
들어봐! 소릴 지르고 있어!
-Rope him. -Cage him!
- 묶어! - 가뒤!
It's not working.
소용 없어요
I can hear you, but their ears aren't strong enough.
소리가 너무 작아요
We need to be louder!
더 크게 외쳐요!
Get every Who to make noise! Everyone!
다 불러와요! 한명도 빠짐없이!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
여기 있어요! 여기 있어요! 여기 있어요!
JoJo! Where are you going?
조조, 어디 가니?
We need every voice! JoJo!
너도 같이 외쳐야지! 조조!
You need to make some noise down there, or we'll all be destroyed!
더 크게 외쳐요 안 그러면 끝장이에요!
The Mayor grabbed a tom-tom and started to smack it,
시장은 북을 치기 시작했쇼
and all over Whoville, they whooped up a racket.
주민들은 난리법석을 피웠습니다
They rattled tin kettles! They beat on brass pans!
양절 솔, 프라이팬
On garbage pail tops and old cranberry cans!
쓰레기통 뚜검을 두드려됐고
They blew on bazookas and blasted great teats.
호른과 트롬본을 불어랬어요
On clarinets, oompahs, and boompahs, and flutes!
클라리넷, 튜바 플루트까지 동원됐쇼
There!
어때?
Can they hear us now?
이젠 들리나?
Listen, please. It's the most beautiful thing ever.
들어봐 너무나 아름다운 소리야!
I don't hear nothing!
아무것도 안 들려!
I don't think so. But keep trying.
안들려요 계속 소릴 내요!
I'll never give in!
난 포기 안 해!
Are you sure that every Who down in Whoville is trying?
한명도 안 빼고 소리내는 거 맞아요?
We are here! We are here!
여기 있어요! 여기 있어요!
Where's JoJo?
조조는?
Probably at the old observatory.
관측대에 갔나 봐요
Hey! There's a limit!
나도 더는 못 참아!
That's not supposed to stretch that far!
코 떨어져 그만 당겨!
JoJo!
조조!
You built this?
네가 다 만든 거니?
We are here! We are here! We are here!
여기 있어요! 여기 있어요! 여기 있어요!
You're making a mistake.
너 실수하는 거야
But, Mom!
엄마!
This doesn't concern you, sweetie. Back in your pouch!
년 참견 마 방으로 들어가!
Everybody! Don't stop!
여러분, 멈추지 말아요!
Keep going! This is gonna do it!
계속해요! 꼭 들을 거예요!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
여기 있어요! 여기 있어요! 여기 있어요!
Can they hear?
들려?
No!
아뇨!
No matter what happens, I couldn't ask for a better son.
무슨 일이 있든 년 최고의 아들이야
Hey, JoJo!
조조!
Come on! Keep going!
계속해요! 쉬지 말고!
No!
안돼!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
여기 있어요! 여기 있어요! 여기 있어요!
Yopp!
압!
I hear it! I hear it!
들려요! 들려요!
They are there!
사람들 소리!
And that Yopp, that one small extra Yopp put it over,
그 '암' 소리를 신호로
and all the Whe noises burst out of the clover.
마을의 소리는 꽃잎 밖으로 터져나왔어요
-l hear it! -Me, too!
- 들려! - 나도!
Rudy. Give me that! Come...
루디, 그거 내나 어서!
Rudy. Get back in the pouch. Now!
루디, 방으로 들어가 냉큼!
No, Mom.
싫어요
Wickershams! Get that clover!
위커샘 형제, 뱃어와!
Anybody! Take it from him!
누구든 가서 뱃어와!
You did it, Mayor. You did it.
해내셨어요! 해냈다고요!
We did it!
성공이에요!
Yeah!
만세!
Well done, son.
잘했다, 아들아
All right, Mayor!
시장님 만세!
Dad, you're one of the greats!
아빠, 캡짱 멋져요!
Whoa. Easy, everyone! Easy!
됐어 이제 그만 해!
Hi, Vlad.
안녕, 블래드
Well, ! shouldn't, but...
뭐 이런 걸 다 고마워!
Oh, man, that is nice touch.
정말 흐못한 장면이군
lam a mess with this, right? Emotional! Here come the waterslide.
난 감동하면 울커해 왜 날 울리는 거야?
There's so many people to thank.
모두들 정말 고마워
The good people of Nool,
날 가두고
who put me in a cage and poked me with sticks.
막대기로 찔러댄 친구들도
That was me!
나야!
My buddy Morton, for being the only one who stood by me.
홀로 내 결을 지켜준 모튼도
Well, not right by me.
내 결은 아니고
He hid in the bushes, sending me good thoughts. He's small.
숲 속에 숨어서 내 정보망이 되어줬지
Dude, you are a warrior poet.
용감한 데다 말도 잘해
And most of all, I'd like to thank the Mayor of Whoville,
시장님께 가장 감사하고 싶어
whe believed in me from the beginning.
늘 날 믿어주셨지
Horton, we're going to miss you.
호튼 자네가 그리울 거야
What are we gonna do without you, Horton?
이제 우리끼리 어쩌죠?
Don't worry. I'll always be around.
걱정 마 늘 가까이에 있을게
And even as I wander
어딜 가나
I'm keeping you in sight
늘 그대와 함께할게요
You're a candle in the window
그대는 창가의 촛불
On a cold, dark winter's night
겨울 밤을 밝히네
Beautiful metaphor.
멋진 비유군
And I'm getting closer
그대 결으로
Than ever thought I might
한발 더 가까이 다가가려오
That's a little high for me.
음이 높아요
Baby, l can't fight this feeling anymore
이 마음을 이젠 숨길 수 없다오
I've forgotten what I started fighting for
처음의 열정을 되찾을 수 있다면
And if l have to crawl upen your floor
기어서라도 찾아가리라
Crawl upon the floor
찾아가리라
Come crashing through your door
그대의 집 문 앞으로
Baby, l can't fight this feeling anymore
이 마음 숨길 수 없어
lean't fight this feeling anymore
이젠 더 이상
And so all ended well, for both Horton and Whos,
모두 행복했죠 호튼도, 누군가 마을도
and for all in the jungle, even kangaroos.
정글의 동물들도 캠거루도
So let that be a lesson, to one and to all.
다들 큰 교훈을 배웠어요
A person's a person, ne matter how small.
아무리 작아도 생명은 소중하다는 거!
And can't fight this feeling anymore
이젠 더 이상 숨길 수 없어
Yeah, I like this. Faster, more up-tempo.
박자가 빠른 게 훨씬 낮네
I've forgotten what I started fighting for
처음의 열정을 되찾을 수 있다면
lean't fight this feeling
이 마음 숨길 수 없어
It's time to bring my ship into your shore
당신 항구에 내 배를 정박할 시간이야
That's a metaphor!
그것도 비유네
And throw away the oar
노는 집어던져
Another metaphor!
비유가 또 나왔어
And buy an engine
엔진을 사
‘Cause I can't fight this feeling anymore
당신이 너무 그리워
From the weight of my trunk to my toes
코끝에서 발끝까지
I've forgotten what I started fighting for
처음의 열정을 되찾을 수 있다면
Well, you shouldn't be fighting anything. Enjoy yourself.
당연히 되찾을 수 있고말고요
If l have to crawl across the floor
기어서라도 찾아가리라
-Now, break down your stupid door -Crashing through your door
- 당신 집 문을 부쉬네릴 거야 - 부쉬버릴 거야
Baby, l can't fight this feeling anymore
이 마음 숨길 수 없어
On an empty stomach
너무 배고파
lean't fight this feeling
이 마음 숨길 수 없어
I'm just saying words.
아무 의미도 없는 말이었어요
That felt so good. Cathartic!
10년 묵은 체증이 확 가셨어! 속 시원타!
What?
뭐?